今天我想做两件事，我想结束对动物园管理员的讨论，
today I want to do two things I want to
finish the discussion of zookeeper and
然后谈论破解我最感兴趣的特定事物
then talk about crack the particular
things that I'm most interested in
谈论不良的动物园管理员的是其API的设计，该API允许
talking about a bad zookeeper are the
design of its API that allows the
Zookeeper成为一项真正的目标通用服务
zookeeper to be a general-purpose
service that really bites off
分布式系统需要执行的重要任务，所以为什么要知道为什么
significant tasks that distributed
systems need so why is this you know why
是一个好的API设计，然后是mini的更具体的主题
is that a good API design and then the
really more specific topic of mini
交易证明这是一个值得了解的主意，因此他们有了API
transactions turns out this is a
worthwhile idea to know so they got API
而且我只是基于筏子的动物园管理员，所以我们可以想到它
and I'm just just a recall zookeepers
based on raft and so we can think of it
因为存在，并且确实是容错的，并且在以下方面做对了
as being and indeed it is fault tolerant
and does the right thing with respect to
分区具有这种性能增强，通过读取
partitions it has this sort of
performance enhancement by which reads
可以在任何副本上进行处理，因此读取结果可能过时，因此我们
can be processed at any replica and
therefore the reads can be stale so we
我们在分析Zookeeper的各种用途时只需记住这一点
just have to keep this in mind as we're
analyzing various uses of the zookeeper
另一方面，zookeeper的接口可以确保每个副本
interface on the other hand zookeeper
does guarantee that every replicas
与所有副本一次一次地处理权限流
process the stream of rights in order
one at a time with all replicas
以相同的顺序执行权限，以便副本在其中进行排序
executing the rights in the same order
so that the replicas advance sort of in
它们的状态完全相同，并且所有操作
their states of all than exactly the
same way and that all of the operation
读取和写入由单个客户端生成的或由客户端处理的
reads and writes produced by a generated
by a single client or processed by the
系统也按照客户发出订单的顺序进行排序，
system also in order both in the order
that the client issued them in and
给定客户端的后续操作始终会看到相同的状态，或者
successive operations from a given
client always see the same state or
在右流中稍后作为上一个读取操作对
later in the right stream as the
previous read operation right any
可以从该客户端进行操作，所以在介绍API外观之前
operation from that client okay so
before I dive into what the API looks
喜欢它，为什么有用，值得思考一下什么类型的问题
like and why it's useful it's worth just
thinking about what kinds of problems
动物园管理员旨在解决或有望解决这样的问题
zookeeper is aiming to solve or could be
expected to solve so
对我来说，这是一个完全核心的动机例子
for me
a totally central example of motivation
为什么要使用ooh keeper的原因是它作为
of why you would want to use ooh keeper
this is it as an implementation of the
测试并设置vmware ft所需的服务，以便任一服务器
test and set service that vmware ft
required in order for either server to
接管另一个失败时，这在vmware中有点神秘
take over when the other one failed it
was a bit of a mystery in the vmware
本文是什么测试即时服务是什么
paper
what is this test instant service how is
您可能知道容错本身是否可以容忍分区，但是
it may you know is it fault tolerant
does it itself tolerate partitions but
Zookeeper实际上为我们提供了编写容错测试和设置的工具
zookeeper actually gives us the tools to
write a fault tolerant test and set
完全是vmware ft所需的那种容错和
service of exactly the kind that vmware
ft needed that is fault tolerant and
确实在分区下做正确的事情，这是一种核心的事情
does do the right thing under partitions
that's sort of a central kind of thing
动物园管理员所做的还有很多其他方法
that zookeepers doing there's also a
bunch of other ways that turns out
人们使用它suki非常成功，人们将其用于很多东西
people use it suki was very successful
people use it for a lot of stuff one
人们使用的东西只是发布配置信息
kind of thing people use is just to
publish just configuration information
供其他服务器使用，例如当前服务器的IP地址
for other servers to use like for
example the IP address of the current
某些工人的主人这只是配置配置信息
master for some set of workers this is
just config configuration information
动物园管理员的另一种经典用法是，如果我们想选一位您知道的主人
another classic use of zookeepers to
elect a master you know if we want to
当老主人失败时，我们需要让每个人都同意新主人
have a when the old master fails we need
to have everyone agree on who the new
师父是，并且即使有分区，也只能选出一位师父
master is and only elect one master even
if there's partitions you can elect a
如果使用少量说明的master，则使用zookeeper原语的master
master using zookeeper primitives if the
master for small amounts of stated
无论如何，如果您选择的主人需要保持某种状态，
anyway if whatever master you elect
needs to keep some state it needs to
保持最新状态，例如您可能知道哪些信息是主要用户
keep it up-to-date like maybe you know
informations such as who the primary is
对于给定的数据块，您可以在GFS中将其存储
for a given chunk of data like you'd
want in GFS the master can store its
动物园管理员的状态，它知道新的饲养者不会失去它，如果主人
state in zookeeper it knows new keepers
not going to lose it if the master
崩溃，我们选择一个新的母版来替换它，新母版可以读取
crashes and we elect a new master to
replace it that new master can just read
老主人国家从动物园管理员那里出来，并依靠它实际上是
the old master state right out of
zookeeper and rely on it actually being
还有其他你可能想像的事情，也许你
there
other things you might imagine maybe you
知道MapReduce这样的系统工作人员可以通过创建来注册自己
know MapReduce like systems workers
could register themselves by creating
小文件和Zookeeper，然后再使用MapReduce之类的系统
little files and zookeeper and again
with systems like MapReduce you can
想象主人通过写东西告诉工人要做什么
imagine the master telling the workers
what to do by writing things in
动物园管理员喜欢在动物园管理员中写一份工作清单，然后是工人的一份清单
zookeeper like writing lists of work in
zookeeper and then worker sort of take
从动物园管理员中逐一删除这些工作项，然后将其删除
those work items one by one out of
zookeeper and delete them as they
完成它们，但人们使用Zookeeper处理所有这些问题
complete them but people use zookeeper
for all these things question
是的
yeah
是的，所以问题是，人们如何使用Zookeeper，通常
exactly yeah so the question is oh how
people use zookeeper and in generally
是的，如果您要运行一些大数据中心，而您要运行所有
yeah you you would if you're running
some big data center and you run all
您知道数据中心中的各种内容Web服务器存储系统
kinds of stuff in your data center you
know web servers storage systems
知道您可能会解雇一个动物园管理员的MapReduce一个动物园管理员集群
MapReduce who knows what you might fire
up a zookeeper one zookeeper cluster
因为这个通用目的可用于很多事情，所以您知道五个或
because this general purpose can be used
for lots of things so you know five or
七个Zookeeper副本，然后在部署各种服务时设计
seven zookeeper replicas and then as you
deploy various services you would design
在您的一个动物园管理员中存储一些关键状态的服务
the services to store some of the
critical state in your one zookeeper
集群好吧，API zookeeper在某些级别上看起来像文件系统
cluster alright the API zookeeper looks
like a filesystem some levels it's got a
目录层次结构，您知道有一个根目录，然后也许
directory hierarchy you know there's a
root directory and then maybe you could
也许每个应用程序都有自己的子目录，所以应用程序可能
maybe each application has its own sub
directory so maybe the application one
将其文件保存在此目录应用程序中，两个将其文件保存在此目录中
keeps its files here in this directory
app two keeps its files in this
目录，您知道这些目录下面都有文件和目录
directory and you know these directories
have files and directories underneath
他们这样做的原因之一就是因为你
them
one reason for this is just because you
守护者就像刚才提到的，是许多人之间共享的设计
keeper is like just mentioned is a
design to be shared between many
可能无关的活动，我们只需要一个命名系统就可以保持
possibly unrelated activities we just
need a naming system to be able to keep
这些活动提供的信息各不相同，因此不会引起混淆，并且
the information from these activities
distinct so they don't get confused and
事实证明，在每个应用程序中错误地读取彼此的数据
read each other's data by mistake
within each application it turns out
使用Zookeeper的许多便捷方法将涉及创建多个
that a lot of convenient ways of using
zookeeper will involve creating multiple
几分钟后，让我们来看几个这样的示例，看起来
files let's see a couple examples like
this in a few minutes okay so it looks
就像文件系统，这是您知道的不是很深，不是，实际上不是
like a filesystem this is you know not
very deep it doesn't it's not actually
您知道您无法真正将其像文件系统那样使用
you know you can't really use it like a
file system in the sense of mounting it
并运行LS和cat以及所有这些内容，就在内部
and running LS and cat and all those
things it's just that internally it
用这些路径名来命名对象，所以您知道这个x y＆z这里的几个
names objects with these path names so
you know one this x y&z here few
与我交谈时您知道的不同文件会发送RPC-Zookeeper说
different files you know when you talk
to me you send an RPC - zookeeper saying
您知道请阅读此数据，然后将其命名为您想要的数据，也许加起来
you know please read this data you would
name the data you want maybe add up to
斜线X这些只是一种分层命名方案
slash X there's just a sort of
hierarchical naming scheme these these
文件和目录称为Z节点，事实证明它是三个
files and directories are called Z nodes
and it turns out it's there's three
您必须了解的类型可以帮助您解决或解决各种问题
types you have to know about that helps
you keep or solve various problems for
我们只有普通的Z节点，如果您创建一个Z节点，它将永久存在，直到您
us there's just regular Z nodes where if
you create one it's permanent until you
删除它，有一个股骨Z节点，如果客户创建一个临时Z
delete it there's a femoral Z nodes
where if a client creates an ephemeral Z
节点动物园管理员认为该临时Z节点会删除该临时Z节点
node zookeeper will delete that
ephemeral Z node if it believes that the
客户死亡，它实际上与客户会话相关，因此客户必须进行排序
client has died it's actually tied to
client sessions so clients have to sort
每隔一段时间就会向动物园管理员发送一点心跳
of send a little heartbeat in every once
a while into the zookeeper into
动物园管理员说哦，我还活着，我还活着，所以动物园管理员不会删除
zookeeper say oh I'm still alive I'm
still alive so zookeeper won't delete
他们的临时文件和最后的特征文件可能是
their ephemeral files and the last
characteristic files may have is
顺序的，这意味着当您要求创建具有给定名称的文件时，
sequential and that means when you ask
to create a file with a given name what
您实际上最终创建的是具有该名称但带有数字的文件
you actually end up creating is a file
with that name but with a number
附加在主体和Zookeeper上的内容如果出现以下情况，则永远不会重复
appended to the main and zookeeper
guarantees never to repeat a number if
多个客户端尝试同时创建顺序文件，
multiple clients try to create
sequential files at the same time and
也要始终对序列号使用montt递增数字
also to always use montt increasing
numbers for the for the sequence numbers
这些是文件名的笔，我们将在示例中看到所有这些内容
that are pens to filenames and we'll see
all of these things come up in examples
在一个层次上，zookeeper公开的RPC接口的操作是排序的
at one level the operations the RPC
interface that zookeeper exposes is sort
您可能希望对文件进行的操作是在其中创建RPC的地方创建RPC。
of what you might expect for your files
was to create RPC where you give it a
确实是一个完整的路径名称，一些初始数据和一些组合
name really a full path name some
initial data and some combination of
这些标记和create的有趣语义是它的专有性是
these flags and interesting semantics of
create is that it's exclusive that is
当我将创建的内容发送给Zookeeper时，请它创建一个文件，以便您保留
when I send a create into zookeeper ask
it to create a file so you keep your
如果该文件不存在并且我是第一个客户端，则回答是或否
responds with a yes or no if that file
didn't exist and I'm the first client
谁想要创建它，zookeeper会说是并创建文件
who wants to create it zookeeper says
yes and creates the file the file
已经存在的动物园管理员说“否”或返回错误，以便客户知道
already exists zookeeper says no or
returns an error so clients know it's
独占创建和客户知道他们是否是一个客户，如果
exclusive create and clients know
whether they were the one client if
多个客户端正在尝试创建我们将在锁定中看到的相同文件
multiple clients are trying to create
the same file which we'll see in locking
样本客户会知道他们是否
samples
the clients will know whether they were
实际设法创建文件的人
the one who actually managed to create
the file
也有删除，我没提到的一件事是容易注释
there's also delete and one thing I
didn't mention is ever easy note has a
版本作为当前版本号，随着修改和删除而增加
version as a current version number that
advances as its modified and delete
连同其他一些更新操作，您可以发送一个版本号，说明
along with some other update operations
you can send an a version number saying
仅当文件的当前版本号是版本时才执行此操作
only do this operation if the files
current version number is the version
指定的内容，如果您担心在
that was specified and that'll turn out
to be helpful if you're worried about in
多个客户端可能试图在以下位置执行相同操作的情况
situations where multiple clients might
be trying to do the same operation at
同时，因此您可以传递一个版本，说只有删除存在
the same time so you can pass a version
saying only delete there's an exists
叫哦，这个名为Xenu的路径是否存在一个有趣的额外参数是
call oh does this path named Xenu exist
an interesting extra argument is that
您可以要求监视是否更改了您指定的任何路径名
you can ask to watch for changes to
whatever path name you specified you can
说明此路径名是否存在，以及是否存在，如果存在
say does this path name exist and
whether or not exists it exists now if
如果您为该手表传递了true，则设置该手表。zookeeper保证
you set this watch if you pass in true
for this watch flag zookeeper guarantees
通知客户端有关该路径名的任何更改（例如创建的内容）
to notify the client if anything changes
about that path name like it's created
或删除或修改，此外还要检查文件是否
or deleted or modified and furthermore
the the check for whether the file
存在并且观看信息中的监视点的设置
exists and the setting of the watch
point of the watching information in the
在动物园管理员内部或原子内部，因此在
inside zookeeper or atomic so nothing
can happen between the point at which
动物园管理员看写流中的点以查看路径
the point in the write stream which
zookeeper looks to see whether the path
存在，并且写流中动物园管理员插入手表的位置
exists and the point in the write stream
at which zookeeper inserts the watch
进入表格，这对于确保正确性非常重要，我们也
into its table and then that's like very
important for for correctness we also
得到D，那么你得到一条路径，再次得到手表标志，现在手表
get D then you get a path and again the
watch flag and now the watch just
适用于该文件的内容有设置数据
applies to the contents of that file
there's set data
再次路径新数据和​​此条件版本，如果您通过
again path the new data and this
conditional version that if you pass an
反转，那么Zookeeper仅在当前版本的情况下才能正确执行
inversion then zookeeper only actually
does the right if the current version
文件的数量等于您传递的数量，所以让我们来看一下
number of the file is equal to the
number you passed in okay so let's see
我们如何使用它，第一个也许几乎第一个非常简单的例子是
how we use this the first maybe almost
this first very simple example is
假设我们在zookeeper中有一个文件，我们想在其中存储一个数字
supposing we have a file in zookeeper
and we want to store a number in that
文件，我们希望能够增加该数字，因此我们可能保留一个
file and we want to be able to increment
that number so we're keeping maybe a
统计信息计数，并且只要您知道的客户知道从
statistics count and whenever a client
you know I know gets a request from a
网络用户或将要增加的数字，在Zookeeper中
web user or something it's going to
increment that count in zookeeper and
一个以上的客户可能想要增加至关重要的数量
more than one client may want to
increment the count that's the critical
一个例子，所以可以避免的一件事是我们是否
thing so an example so one thing to sort
of get out of the way is whether we
实际上需要一些专门的界面来支持客户协调
actually need some specialized interface
in order to support client coordination
与数据相反，这看起来像文件系统，我们可以只提供
as opposed to just data this looks like
a file system could we just provide the
普通的读写类型的文件系统，可以追溯到典型的存储
ordinary readwrite kind of file system
stuff that dated that typical storage
系统提供的信息，例如，您中的一些人已经开始，而您将全部开始
systems provide so for example some of
you have started and you'll all start
很快就会添加3，您将在其中构建键值存储，其中有两个操作
soon Ladd 3 in which you build a key
value store where the two operations are
唯一的操作就是放置关键值，所以一个问题是我们可以吗
the only operations are put key value
and so one question is can we do you
知道我们可能想要与Zookeeper一起做的所有这些事情
know all these things that we might want
to do with zookeeper can we just do them
与实验室3与具有键值的键放置get接口，所以假设我
with lab 3 with a key with a key value
put get interface so supposing for my I
想要实现这个计数的事情，也许我可以用
want to implement this count thing maybe
I could implement the count with just
实验室三分法键值接口，因此您可以通过说x来增加计数
lab threes key value interface so you
might increment the count by saying x
等于让您知道正在使用的密钥，然后将该密钥加X加1
equals get you know whatever key were
using and then put that key an X plus 1
为什么这是一个错误的答案，是的，是的，哦，不是原子的，这绝对是
why why is this a bad answer yes yes oh
it's not atomic that is absolutely the
问题的根源，您知道将其放入的抽象方法，但是一个
root of the problem here and you know
the abstract way of putting it but one
看它的方式是两个客户都想增加
way of looking at it is that of two
clients both want to increment the
同时他们都将阅读他们都将使用获取
counter at the same time they're both
gonna read they're both gonna use get to
阅读旧值，让您知道十，那将加一到十，得到11
read the old value and get you know ten
those gonna add one to ten and get 11
我本来跟11跟注，所以现在我们把计数器增加了一个，但是
and I was gonna call put with 11 so now
we've increased the counter by one but
两个客户都在这样做，所以我们肯定应该增加它
two clients were doing it so surely we
should have ended up increasing it by
两个，这就是为什么即使这个简单的例子也不能使用实验三的原因
two so that's why the lab three cannot
be used for even this simple example
此外，在那种动物园管理员世界中，访客可以返回过时的数据
furthermore in the sort of zookeeper
world where guests can return stale data
不是实验3或不允许get返回过时的数据，但是在zookeeper中读取
is not lab 3 or gets are not allowed to
return stale data but in zookeeper reads
可能是过时的，因此，如果您阅读了当前计数器的过时版本并添加了
can be stale and so if you read a stale
version of the current counter and add
一个它，你现在写错了你的价值
one to it
you're now writing the wrong value you
知道30的值是否为11但您得到的返回陈旧值10，则将1加
know if 30 values 11 but you're get
returns a stale value of 10 you add 1 to
并输入11，这是一个错误，因为我们真的应该一直输入12，
that and put 11 that's a mistake because
we really should have been putting 12 so
动物园管理员还有其他问题，我们必须为此担心
zookeeper has this additional problem
that we have to worry about that
不会返回最新数据
that gets don't return the latest data
好的，那么您将如何在Zookeeper中执行此操作，这就是我将如何在Zookeeper中执行此操作
ok so how would you do this in zookeeper
here's how I would do this in zookeeper
事实证明，您需要做的事情是将西门子代码包装在一个循环中，因为
it turns out you need to do you need to
wrap this code Siemens in a loop because
不能保证第一次就能成功，所以我们只能说是真的
it's not guaranteed to succeed the first
time so we're just gonna say while true
我们将调用获取数据来获取计数器的当前值和
we're gonna call get data to get the
current value of the counter and the
当前版本，所以我们要说XV等于我有数据，我们需要说
current version so we're gonna say X V
equals I'm get data and we need to say
最终名称，我不在乎文件名是什么，我们只是说很好，现在我们得到了
final name I don't care what the file
name is we just say that nice now we get
我们得到的值和版本号可能不是新鲜的，可能是陈旧的
the well we get a value and a version
number possibly not fresh possibly stale
但也许是新鲜的，然后我们将使用有条件的放置条件设置
but maybe fresh and then we're gonna use
a conditional put a conditional setting
如果set data是set data操作，则返回true表示它确实设置了
and if set data is a set data operation
return true meaning it actually did set
我们要打破的价值，否则就回到循环的顶部
the value we're gonna break otherwise
just go back to the top of the loop
否则，这里发生的是我们读取了一些值和一些版本
otherwise so what's going on here is
that we read some value and some version
可能仍然是复制品中新的数字，我们发送的设置数据
number maybe still maybe fresh out of
the replicas the set data we send
实际上是动物园管理员的负责人，因为所有权利都归于该负责人，
actually did the zookeeper leader
because all rights go to the leader and
这意味着仅将值设置为X加一个（如果带实数的版本
what this means is only set the value to
X plus one if the version with the real
版本最新的版本仍然是V，因此如果我们读取新数据却什么也没有
version the latest version is still is V
so if we read fresh data and nothing
像其他客户端一样尝试在系统中进行其他操作
然后，我们将读取最新版本的最新值，然后将最新值添加一个
this then we'll read the latest version
latest value we'll add one to the latest
值指定最新版本，我们的设置数据将被领导者接受
value specify the latest version and our
set data will be accepted by the leader
提交后，我们将获得对我们要求的肯定答复，
and we'll get back a positive reply to
our request after it's committed and
我们会中断，因为如果我们这里有过时的数据或者这是新鲜的数据，我们就完成了
we'll break because we're done if we got
stale data here or this was fresh data
但是到了我们的设定数据到达领导者的时候
but by the time
our set data got to the leader some
其他客户端设置数据，而其他客户端正在尝试增加其设置
other clients set data and some other
client is trying to increment their set
我们之前收到的数据我们的版本号都不会再更新
data got there before us our version
number will no longer be fresh in either
在这种情况下，此设置的数据将失败，我们将返回错误响应
those cases this set data will fail and
we'll get an error response back it
不会脱离循环，我们将返回并重试，希望我们会
won't break out of the loop and we'll go
back and try again and hopefully we'll
这次成功了，是的，所以问题是这是一个while循环
succeed this time yes yes so the
question is could this it's a while loop
否则我们保证永远完成，不，不，我们不是真的保证
or we guaranteed is ever going to finish
and no no we're not really guaranteed
我们将在实践中完成，例如，如果我们的复制品是
that we're gonna finish in practice you
know so for example if our replicas were
从领导者那里截取信息并永久地给我们提供过时的数据，然后
reading from is cut off from the leader
and permanently gives us stale data then
你知道也许这不会解决，但是你知道，但是在现实生活中
you know maybe this is not gonna work
out but you know but in real life well
在现实生活中，您知道领导者将所有复制品推向
in real life the you know leaders
pushing all the replicas towards having
与领导者相同的数据，所以您可能知道我们是否刚刚获得过时的数据
identical data to the leader so you know
if we just got stale data here probably
当我们回去时，你知道也许我们应该睡10毫秒左右
when we go back you know maybe we should
sleep for 10 milliseconds or something
在这一点上，但是当我们回到这里最终我们会看到最新的
at this point but when we go back here
eventually we're gonna see the latest
数据的情况下，这可能真的是一个坏消息是
data the situation under which this
might genuinely be pretty bad news is if
如果我们知道，客户会有非常高的连续增量负载
there's a very high continuous load of
increments from clients you know if we
有一千个客户都试图增加的风险是，也许没有
have a thousand clients all trying to do
increments the risk is that maybe none
他们中的一些会成功，或者我认为其中之一会成功，因为我
of them will succeed or something I
think one of them will succeed because I
认为最成功的一个是因为您知道第一个获得成功的人
think one of the most succeed because
you know the the first one that gets its
将数据设置为领导者将成功，其余的都将失败，因为
set data into the leader will succeed
and the rest will all fail because their
版本号都太低，然后下一个999将放入并获取数据
version numbers are all too low and then
the next 999 will put and get data's in
他们中的一个会成功，所以它们都具有N平方的复杂度
and one of them will succeed so it all
have a sort of N squared complexity to
通过所有其他客户，这是非常有害的，但这会
get through all of the all other clients
which is very damaging but it will
最终完成，所以如果您认为自己会有很多客户，
finish eventually and so if you thought
you were gonna have a lot of clients you
会在这里使用其他策略这很好
would use a different strategy here this
is good
或加载情况是，如果它们适合内存，那么如果它们不适合就没问题
or load situations yes if they fit in
memory it's no problem if they don't fit
记忆是一场灾难，所以是的，当您使用Zookeeper时，必须保持
memory it's a disaster so yeah when
you're using zookeeper you have to keep
请记住，它非常适合100 MB的内容，并且可能
in mind that it's yeah it's great for
100 megabytes of stuff and probably
可怕的是100 GB的内容，这就是为什么人们认为它可以存储
terrible for 100 gigabytes of stuff so
that's why people think of it as storing
配置信息，而不是您的大型网站的旧数据
configuration information rather than
their we old data of your big website
是的，我的意思是监视这个序列
yes I mean it's sort of watch into this
sequence
但是如果想要的话，可能会是这样，如果我们想修复此问题以使其在高
yet that could be so if we want if we
wanted to fix this to work under high
负载，那么您肯定会在我身体不好的时候入睡
load then you would certainly want to
sleep at this point where I'm not well
我解决这个问题的本能我解决这个问题的方法是插入睡眠
the way I would fix this my instinct I'm
fixing this would be to insert asleep
在这里，此外，它的数量是随机睡眠的两倍
here and furthermore double the amount
of it sort of randomized sleep whose
每当我们失败时，随机范围就会加倍，这是一种尝试和真实
span of randomness doubles each time we
fail and that's a sort of tried and true
策略指数回退实际上是和筏长相似的
strategies exponential back-off is a
it's actually similar to raft leader
选举是适应未知数的合理策略
election it's a reasonable strategy for
adapting to an unknown number of
并发客户端，好吧，告诉我什么是好吧，所以我们正在获取数据
concurrent clients so okay tell me
what's right okay so we're getting data
然后看它的真实
and then watching its true
所以是的，如果有人在您调用设置数据之前修改了数据，也许
so yes so if somebody else modifies the
data before you call set data maybe
您会收到一个手表通知，问题是计时不起作用
you'll get a watch notification um the
problem is the timing is not working in
您的青睐就像我在这里收到数据之间的时间间隔
your favor like the amount of time
between when I received the data here
当我向领导发送消息时，新设置的数据为零
and when I send off the message to the
leader with this new set data is zero
那大概是多少时间在这里经过，如果有其他客户被发送
that's how much time will pass here
roughly and if some other client is sent
大约在这个时候增加，实际上，
in increment at about this time it's
actually quite a long time between when
客户发送增量，并在其通过领导者工作时发送
that client sends in the increment and
when it works its way through the leader
并发送给关注者并实际执行关注者和
and is sent out to the followers and
actually executed the followers and the
追随者在手表表中查找并向我发送通知，因此我
followers look it up in their watch
table and send me a notification so I
认为
think
它不会给您任何阅读结果，或者如果您要阅读的内容是在某个时候阅读的话
it won't give you any read result or if
you read at a point if you're gonna read
在发生修改的那一点之后，
at a point that's after where the
modification occurred that should raise
手表，您将在阅读之前得到手表的通知
the watch you'll get the notification of
the watch before you get the read
回应，但无论如何，我认为这样的事情无法拯救我们，因为
response but in any case I think nothing
like this could save us because what's
将会发生的是，成千上万的客户都会做同样的事情，无论它是什么
gonna happen is all thousand clients are
gonna do the same thing whatever it is
没错，他们都会再次做并设置手表，无论他们做什么
right they're all gonna do again and set
a watch and whatever they're all gonna
同时收到通知，他们都会做出相同的决定
get the notification at the same time
they're all gonna make the same decision
关于他们，他们都不会去看，因为他们都没有做过
about well they're all not gonna get to
watch because none of them has done the
正确放置数据，因此最坏的情况是所有客户端
put data yet right
so the worst case is all the clients are
从同一点开始，他们都做了，他们都得到了版本一，他们都
starting at the same point they all do a
get they all get version one they all
设置观察点，他们不会收到通知，因为没有任何变化
set a watch point they don't get a
notification because no change has
发生了，他们都向领导者发送了一组数据RPC给领导者，
occurred they all send a set data RPC to
the leader all thousand of them the
第一个更改数据，现在更改另一个999，并在以下情况时收到通知
first one changes the data and now the
other 999 and get a notification when
为时已晚，因为他们已经发送了设置数据，所以很可能
it's too late because they've already
sent the set data so it's possible that
手表可以在这里为我们提供帮助，但是我拥有的手表的简单版本
watch could help us here but sort of
straightforward version of watch I have
如果您想收到我们会在几分钟内讨论的邮件
a feeling if you wanted the the mail
we'll talk about this in a few minutes
但是匿名听到第二个锁定示例绝对解决了这种问题
but the anon heard the second locking
example absolutely solves this kind of
问题，因此我们可以适应本文中的第二个锁定示例以尝试
problem so we could adapt to the second
locking example from the paper to try to
如果有大量客户，导致一次发生一次增量
cause the increments to happen one at a
time if there's a huge number of clients
谁想要这样做关于这个例子的其他问题好吧，这是一个例子
who want to do it other questions about
this example okay this is an example of
很多人都称其为小型交易
a what many people call a mini
transaction all right it's transactional
从某种意义上说，哇，您知道这里发生了很多有趣的事情
in a sense that wow there's you know a
lot of funny stuff happening here the
效果是，一旦一切成功，我们就取得了原子
effect is that once it all succeeds we
have achieved an atomic
读-修改-写计数器在这里的困难
read-modify-write of the counter right
the difficulty here
是不是正确的读取权限，修改权限的读取权限是原子的
is that it's not atomic the reading the
right the read the modifying the right
不是原子的，我们在这里提出的是这个序列
are not atomic the thing that we have
pulled off here is that this sequence
一旦完成是原子权利，我们实际上就是人，一旦我们必须继续
once it finishes is atomic right we
actually man and once we have to be on
通过成功的传递，我们设法读取增量并写入
the pass through this that we succeeded
we managed to read increment and write
在没有其他干预的情况下，我们成功地完成了这两个步骤
without anything else intervening we
managed to do these two steps atomically
而且您知道这不是因为这不是一个完整的数据库事务，例如
and you know this is not because this
isn't a full database transaction like
真实的数据库允许完全常规的交易，您可以说开始
real databases allow fully general
transactions where you can say start
交易，然后读或写任何您喜欢的东西
transaction and then read or write
anything you like maybe thousands of
不同的数据项，无论谁知道什么，然后说结束交易，
different data items whatever who knows
what and then say end transaction and
数据库将巧妙地将整个事情作为原子事务提交，因此
the database will cleverly commit the
whole thing as an atomic transaction so
实际交易可能非常复杂动物园管理员支持此操作
real transactions can be very
complicated zookeeper supports this
非常简化的版本，您知道什么时候我们可以做到
extremely simplified version of you know
when you're sort of one we can do it
对一件数据进行原子排序操作，但足以获得增量
atomic sort of operations on one piece
of data but it's enough to get increment
以及其他一些原因，因为它们不通用
and some other things so these are for
that reason since they're not general
但它们确实提供了原子性，通常被称为小型交易，
but they do provide atomicity these are
often called mini transactions and it
事实证明，这种模式也可以与其他各种东西一起使用
turns out this pattern can be made to
work with various other things too like
如果我们想进行测试并设置vmware ft要求可以实施
if we wanted to do the test and set that
vmware ft requires it can be implemented
使用此设置，您可能知道旧值是否为零，然后尝试
with very much this setup you know maybe
the old value if it's zero then we try
将其设置为一个，但提供此版本号，您知道没人干预
to set it to one but give this version
number you know nobody else intervened
而我们实际上是将其设置为1的人，因为版本
and we were the one who actually managed
to set it to one because the version
人数没有改变，但我是领导者，我们得到了要求，我们赢得了其他人
number hadn't changed but i'm leader got
our request and we win somebody else
读完后更改为一个，然后领导者会告诉我们我们输了，所以您
changes to one after we read it then the
leader will tell us that we lost so you
也可以测试并使用此模式进行设置，您应该记住，这是
can do test and set with this pattern
also and you should remember this is the
战略
strategy
好的，下一个例子，我想谈的是这些锁，我在说
okay alright next example I want to talk
about is these locks and I'm talking
关于这一点，因为它在论文中，而不是因为我坚信
about this because it's in the paper not
because I strongly believe that this
那种锁很有用，但是他们有一个例子，其中有一个合唱团
kind of lock is useful but they have
they have an example in which a choir
有几个步骤，我们尝试创建一个锁文件，然后尝试创建一个
has a couple steps one we try to create
we have a lock file and we try to create
现在，锁定文件再次将一些股骨设置为true的文件，因此
the lock file now again some file with a
femoral set to true and so if that
那么成功与否，我们已经获得了第二步的锁
succeeds then or not we've acquired the
lock the second step that doesn't
成功，那么我们想等待获得锁的人，如果不是
succeed then we want to wait for whoever
did acquire the lock what if this isn't
是的，这意味着锁定文件已经存在，我的意思是其他人已经获得了
true that means the lock file already
exists I mean somebody else has acquired
锁，所以我们要等待他们释放锁，他们将
the lock and so we want to wait for them
to release the lock and they're gonna
通过删除此文件来释放锁，所以我们要注意
release the lock by deleting this file
so we're gonna watch yes
好了，所以我们要观看，我们要通话存在，观看是真实的
alright so we're gonna watch we're gonna
gonna call exists and watching is true
现在事实证明，嗯，如果文件仍然存在，那
now it turns out that um okay and and
and if the file still exists right which
我们期望如此，因为毕竟它们根本不存在
we expect it to because after all they
didn't exist presumably would have
返回此处，所以如果存在，我们要等待我们正在等待的通知
returned here so if it exists we want to
wait for the notification we're waiting
对于此手表通知，请调用这三个步骤，然后转到下一步
for this watch notification call this
three and a step for go to what so the
通常的交易是您知道我们称之为创造您知道如果我们失败了也许我们会赢
usual deal is you know we call create
you know maybe we win if it fails we
等待拥有锁的人释放它，我们会在何时收到监视通知
wait for whoever owns a lock to release
it we get the watch notification when
此时该文件已删除，等待完成，我们回到周一，
the file is deleted at that point this
wait finishes and we go back to Mon and
尝试重新创建文件，希望这次我们可以获取文件，所以我们
try to recreate the file hopefully we
will get the file this time okay so we
应该问自己一些关于其他客户可能的交织的问题
should ask ourselves questions about
possible interleavings of other clients
我们的四个步骤进行活动，因此我们可以肯定知道
activities with our four steps so one we
know for sure we know of already if
另一个客户在同一时间打电话给create，那么Zookeeper负责人就要去了
another client calls create at the same
time then the zookeeper leader is going
以某种顺序一次处理这两个以创建rpcs
to process those two to create rpcs one
at a time in some order
所以迈克·里德（Mike Reid）会先执行
so either mike reid will be executed
first
否则其他客户创建的将首先执行，首先是
or the other clients create will be
executed first minds executed first i'm
将获得真实的回报并获得锁，而另一个客户端是
going to get a true back in return and
acquire the lock and the other client is
保证会得到错误的回报，如果首先处理了个人电脑，他们将
guaranteed to get a false return and if
there are pcs processed first they'll
得到真实的回报，我保证得到错误的回报
get the true return and i'm guaranteed
to get the false return and in either
文件将被创建的情况下，所以如果我们同时进行
case the file will be created
so we're okay if we have simultaneous
另一个问题的执行情况很好，你知道我是否可以创建
executions of one another question is
well you know if I if create doesn't
为我成功，我要称呼存在，如果锁被释放会发生什么
succeed for me and I'm gonna call exists
what happens if the lock is released
实际上在创建和存在之间
actually between the create and the
exists
所以这就是为什么我说唱我周围有刀的原因是
so this is the reason why I rap I have a
knife around me around the exists is
因为它实际上可能在我打电话之前就被释放了，因为它可以
because it actually might be released
before I call exists because it could
已经很久以前被其他客户收购，如果
have been acquired quite a long time ago
by some other client and then if the
文件不存在，这将失败，我直接
file doesn't exist at this point then
this will fail and I'll just go directly
回到这个，再试一次
back to this go to one and try again
类似地，实际上更有趣的是，如果谁拥有它，将会发生什么
similarly and actually more interesting
is what happens if the whoever holds it
现在释放它，就像我所说的存在一样，或者当我正在与之交谈的副本位于其中时
now releases it just as I call exist or
as the replica I'm talking to is in the
处理我的存在请求的中间，答案是
middle of processing my exists requests
and the answer to that is that the
我正在查看的任何副本都知道它是日志或保证有权利存在
whatever replica I'm looking at you know
it's log or guaranteed that rights occur
以某种顺序正确，所以我要说的是
in some order right
so the repla I'm talking to it's it's
以某种方式记录其进程，并确保我的存在调用得以执行
log its proceeding in some way and my
exists call is guaranteed to be executed
在右流中的两个日志条目之间，这是一个，这是一个
between two log entries in the right
stream right this is a this is a
只读请求，您知道问题是有人删除了
read-only request and you know the
problem is that somebody's delete
大约在这个时间正在处理请求，因此日志中的某个位置
request is being processed at about this
time so somewhere in the log is going
任一个将是来自另一个客户端和代表的删除请求
either is going to be the delete request
from the other client and the rep and
你知道这是我的想法，我正在与动物园管理员复制品交谈
you know this is my mind the replica
that I'm talking to zookeeper replicas
我正在与他的日志交谈，我的手表我存在的RPC已处理
I'm talking to his log my watch my
exists RPC is either processed
此处已完全处理，在这种情况下，副本仍然可以看到文件
completely processed here in which case
the replica sees oh the file still
存在，并且副本将监视信息插入此位置的监视表中
exists and the replica inserts the watch
information into its watch table at this
点，然后才执行删除，因此当删除进来时
point and only then executes the delete
so when the delete comes in were
保证我的监视请求在副本监视表中，并且它将
guaranteed that my watch request is in
the replicas watch table and it will
向我发送通知权限，或者在此处执行我的存在请求
send me a notification right or my exist
requests is executed here at a point
删除发生后，文件不存在，因此现在调用返回true
after the delete happen the file doesn't
exist and so now the call returns true
实际上，监视表条目是
and
no well actually a watch table entry is
进入，但我们不在乎权利，因此权利是非常重要的
entered but we don't care right so it's
quite important that the rights are
排序，并且读取发生在权利之间的确定点上
sequenced and that reads happen at
definite points between rights yes well
好的，是的，所以这是执行存在文件所在的位置
okay so yes so this is where the exists
is executed the file doesn't exist at
这一点存在，返回false，我们等不及要创建文件，
this point exists returns false we don't
wait we go to one we create the file and
返回我们确实在这里安装了一个手表，手表会被触发，它不会
return we did install a watch here that
watch will be triggered it doesn't
真的很重要，因为我们不是真正等待它，但是手表会
really matter because we're not really
waiting for it but the watch will be
由这个触发
triggered by this created
我们不是在等待它，但是是的，所以该文件不存在，我们转到一个
we're not waiting for it but yeah okay
so the file doesn't exist we go to one
有人创建了文件，我们尝试创建失败的文件，
somebody else has created the file we
try to create the file that fails we
安装另一个手表，这是一个dis watch，我们不等待，所以这
方式并不等待任何事情发生，尽管并不重要
way does not a wait for anything to
happen although it doesn't really matter
在此刻尽早退出循环无害，只是
in the moment it's not harmful to to to
break out of this loop early it's just
无论如何，我们都浪费了代码的全部历史记录
wasteful anyway we've all the history
this code leaves watches sort of in the
系统，我真的不知道新手表在同一文件上会覆盖什么
system and I don't really know what does
my new watch on the same file override
我的旧手表我不确定
my old watch I'm not actually sure
好吧，我终于是这个例子了，前面的例子中
okay I'm finally this example and the
previous example suffle suffer from the
牧群效应我们也听到了我们谈到的效应我的意思是我们在说什么
herd effect we also heard effect we
talked about I mean what we were talking
关于我们什么时候担心的，但是如果有客户，我会尝试在
about when we were worrying about oh but
if clients I'll try to increment this at
同时，天哪，N将平方
the same time
gosh that's going to have N squared
达到锁定所有千位客户端所需时间的复杂程度
complexity as far as how long it takes
to get to all thousand clients this lock
如果有一千个客户，该计划也会受到羊群效应的影响
scheme also suffers from the herd effect
in that if there are a thousand clients
尝试获取锁，然后获得授予所需的时间
trying to get the lock then the amount
of time that's required to sort of grant
每千个客户的锁与一千个客户成比例
the lock to each one of the thousand
clients is proportional to a thousand
平方，因为每次发布后都会触发所有其余客户端
squared because after every release all
of the remaining clients get triggered
通过这个手表，所有其余的客户都回到这里并发送
by this watch all of the remaining
clients go back up here and send in a
创建，因此我们生成的pc的创建总数基本上是
create and so the total number create
our pcs generated is basically a
千平方，所以这使这群人遭受了整个等待
thousand squared so this suffers from
this herd the whole herd of waiting
客户殴打动物园管理员另一个名字是因为这不是
clients is beating on zookeeper another
name for this is that it's a non
可伸缩的锁或是的，所以本文是一项真正的交易，我们将拭目以待
scalable lock or yeah okay and so the
paper is a real deal and we'll see it
越来越多的其他系统，很快就严重地解决了问题
more and in other systems and soon
enough serious end of problems the paper
实际谈论了如何使用Zookeeper解决这个问题
actually talks about how to solve it
using zookeeper and the interesting
事实是Zook实际上足以表达
thing is that Zook
it's actually expressive enough to be
能够建立一个不受此伤害影响的更复杂的锁定方案
able to build a more complex lock scheme
that doesn't suffer from this hurt
导致甚至一千个客户都在等待一个客户的成本
effect that even of a thousand clients
are waiting the cost of one client
放弃锁而又获得一个锁的是顺序1而不是顺序n和
giving up a lock and another acquiring
it is order 1 instead of order n and
这是因为这有点复杂，这是
this is the because it's a little bit
complex this is the pseudocode in the
如果您想继续阅读第2.4节中的论文，请参阅第6页，因此是
paper in section 2.4 it's on page 6 if
you want to follow along so this is and
所以这次没有单个锁定文件
so this time there is not a single lock
file
没有，只是一个名字，我们都可以谈论相同
there's no yes it is just a name that
allows us to all talk about the same
锁，这只是一个名字，现在我已经获得了锁，我可以做到
lock so it's just a name know now I've
acquired the lock and I can do I can
无论锁在保护着什么，您一次可能只知道我们一个人
whatever the lock was protecting you
know maybe only one of us at a time
如果您想进行演讲，则应允许在此演讲厅进行演讲
should be allowed to give a lecture in
this lecture hall if you want to give a
在此演讲厅进行的演讲首先，您需要获取名为34100的锁
lecture in this lecture hall you first
have to acquire the lock called 34 100
事实证明，是的，这是Z节点和Zookeeper，但它像没人一样
the that turns out it's yes it's a Z
node and zookeeper but it like nobody
在乎其内容，我们只需要它能够同意一个名称即可
cares about its contents we just need it
to be able to agree on a name for the
锁定就是piyah的感觉，它看起来像文件系统
lock that's the sense in which that's
piyah this it looks like a file system
但这确实是一个命名系统，所以第一步是我们创建一个顺序
but it's really a naming system alright
so step one is we create a sequential
文件
file
所以是的，我们给它起一个前缀名，但实际上它创建的是您是否知道
and so yeah we give it a prefix name but
what it actually creates is you know if
这是使用前缀F创建的第27个文件顺序文件
this is the 27th file sequential file
created with with prefix F you know
也许我们得到F 27之类的东西，然后按照
maybe we get F 27 or something and and
in the sequenced in the sequence of
写道，动物园管理员正在通过连续创建不断提升
writes that zookeeper is it's working
through successive creates get ascending
保证升序从不降序总是升序
guaranteed ascending never descending
always ascending sequence numbers when
您创建一个顺序文件时，有一个操作我从列表中删除了
you create a sequential file there was
an operation I left off from the list it
原来你可以得到一个文件列表，你可以得到下面的文件列表
turns out you can get a list of files
you can get a list of files underneath
您给出Zeno的名称，它实际上是一个包含文件的目录
you give the name of Zeno that's
actually a directory with files in it
您可以获得该目录中当前所有文件的列表，因此我们
you can get a list of all the files that
are currently in that directory so we're
要列出文件，让我们开始，您可能知道列出我们得到的星号
gonna list the files let's start with
that you know maybe list f star we get
返回一些清单，我们创建一个文件，系统在其中分配了一个数字，我们可以
some list back we create a file with the
system allocated us a number here we can
看看这个数字，如果此列表中没有低编号的文件，那么我们赢了
look at that number if there's no lower
numbered file in this list then we win
我们得到了锁，所以如果我们的顺序文件是最低的
and we get the lock
so if our sequential file is the lowest
带有该名称前缀的数字文件，我们赢了，所以没有更低的数字，我们需要锁定
number file with that name prefix we win
so no lower number we've quired the lock
我们可以返回，如果还有一个，那么我们要等待
and we can return if there is one then
again what we want to wait for then
这是因为这些顺序编号的文件正在设置
what's going on is that these
sequentially numbered files are setting
向上将锁授予不同客户端的顺序
up the order in which the lock is going
to be granted to the different clients
因此，如果我们不是锁的赢家，我们需要做的就是等待
so if we're not the winner of the lock
what we need to do is wait for the
先前编号与创建先前编号文件的客户端的编号
previously numbered with the client who
created the previously numbered file to
释放以获取然后释放锁，我们将释放锁
release to acquire and then release the
lock and we're going to release the lock
在该系统中释放锁定的约定是为了
the convention for releasing the locking
in this system is for
删除文件以删除您的顺序文件，所以我们要等待
remove the file to remove your
sequential file so we want to wait for
先前编号的要删除的顺序文件，然后轮到我们
the previously numbered sequential file
to be deleted and then it's our turn and
我们得到了锁，所以我们需要呼叫存在，所以我们要说该呼叫是否
we get the lock so we need to call
exists so we're gonna say if the call
存在主要是为了设置观察点，所以您知道下一个较低编号的文件
exists mostly to set a watch point
so it's you know next lower number file
我们希望有一个手表让该文件仍然存在，我们将等待
and we want to have a watch get that
file still exist we're gonna wait and
然后是步骤5，最后我们要回到
then so that's step 5
and then finally we're gonna go back to
我们不会再次创建文件，因为它已经存在，我们要去
we're not going to create the file again
because it already exists we're gonna go
回到列出的文件，所以这是一个合唱团发布，我删除了
back to listing the yeah the files so
this is a choir releases just I delete
如果我获得了锁，则删除我创建的文件以及其编号
if I acquire the lock I delete my the
file I created complete with my number
是
yes
为什么需要再次列出文件
why do you need to list the files again
这是一个很好的问题，所以问题是我们得到了我们知道的文件列表
that's a good question so the question
is we got the list of files we know the
下一个较低编号的文件有序文件的保证
next lower number file there's a
guarantee of the sequential file
创建的是，一旦提交了27号文件，那么编号较小的文件将不会
creation is that once filed 27 is
created no file with a lower number will
后来被创造出来，所以我们现在知道别无他物，所以
ever subsequently be created so we now
know nothing else could sneak in here so
下一个较低编号的文件怎么知道，为什么我们需要再次列出
how could the next lower number file you
know why why do we need to list again
我们为什么不回去等待同样的低编号文件呢？
why don't we just go back to waiting for
that same lower numbered file thing
小甜甜猜答案
Britney guess the answer
我的意思是该代码的工作方式是问题的答案
I mean the the the way this code works
the answer to the question is whoever
是下一个被降下的人可能至少获得了他的锁
was the next lowered person might have
either acquired him at least the lock
在我们注意到或已经死亡之前，这已经过去了，这些是暂时性文件
before we noticed or have died and this
went and these are transient files sorry
或任何所谓的临时文件，都有一个临时文件，您甚至知道
or whatever they're called ephemeral
there's an ephemeral file you know even
如果我们在第27行中排在第27位，那么在获得锁之前可能已经死亡
if we're 27th in line number 26 may have
died before getting the lock if number
26死后系统会自动删除其临时文件，因此
26 dies the system automatically deletes
their ephemeral files and so if that
现在发生了，我们需要等待25号，这是下一个您知道的所有号码
happened now we need to wait for number
25 that is the next you know it if all
您知道2到27的文件，如果全部都是27，则我们为27
files you know 2 through 27 and and
we're 27 if they're all they are and
他们都在等待锁，如果之前的锁死了
they're all waiting there's a lock if if
the one before is dies before getting
现在锁定，我们需要等待下一个较低的数字文件，不是因为
the lock now we need to wait for the
next next lower number file not because
下一个较低的位置消失了，所以这就是为什么我们必须返回并重新列出
the next lower one is has gone away so
that's why we have to go back and relist
文件，以防我们的前任在等待客户列表中出现
the files in case our predecessor in the
list of waiting clients turned out to
死了
die yes
如果没有编号比您绝对拥有的锁少的文件
if there's no lower numbered file than
you have acquired the lock absolutely
是的，如果我们有一千人，这怎么不会受到羊群效应的影响
yes how does this not suffer from the
herd effect suppose we have a thousand
等待中的客户，目前通过前500名客户
clients waiting and currently client
made through the first five hundred and
客户五百持有锁，每个客户等待每个客户都坐着
client five hundred holds the lock every
client waiting every client is sitting
在这里等待事件，但只有创建文件的客户端五百
here waiting for an event but only the
client that created file five hundred
还有一个他在等待五百个文件的愿景，所以每个人都在等待
and one he's waiting for the vision of
file five hundred so everybody's waiting
下一个较低的数字，所以五百正在等待499二十九
for the next lower number so five
hundred is waiting for 499 twenty nine
九个，但是当我释放该文件时，每个人都在等待一个文件
nine but everybody everybody's waiting
for just one file when I release the
锁定只有一个其他客户端，下一个更高编号的客户端
lock there's only one other client the
next higher numbered client that's
等待我的文件，所以当我释放锁时，一个客户端会收到通知
waiting for my file so when I release
the lock one client gets a notification
一位客户返回并列出文件，一位客户现在一位客户拥有
one client goes back and lists the files
one client and one client now has the
锁定，无论您有多少客户，您都知道这种费用
lock so the sort of expense you know no
matter how many clients that are the
每个发行版和购买版的支出是恒定数量的PC
expense of one of each release and
acquire is a constant number of our PCs
在这里发布和获取的费用是每一个
where's the expense of a release and
acquire here is that every single
等待客户端的通知，每个客户端发送一个写请求
waiting client is notified and every
single one of them sends a write request
比向Zookeeper创建请求
than the create request into zookeeper
哦，你可以自由地喝杯咖啡，是的，我的意思是你知道
oh you're free to get a cup of coffee
yeah I mean this is you know what the
编程接口似乎不是我们的事，但这不是
programming interface looks like is not
our business but this is either and
对于这实际上意味着什么，有两种选择
there's there's two options for what
this actually means as far as what the
程序看起来像是其中一个线程实际上处于同步状态
program looks like one is there's some
thread that's actually in a synchronous
等待它进行了一个函数调用，说请获取此锁，然后
wait it's made a function call saying
please acquire this lock and the
直到最后获得锁或
function hold doesn't return until the
locks finally acquired or the
通知回来，复杂得多的界面将成为一个
notification comes back of much more
sophisticated interface would being one
在其中您解雇请求动物园管理员，不要等待，然后
in which you fire off requests a
zookeeper and don't wait and then
分开说的话，有一种看得见的方式
separately there's some way of seeing
well as you keep your said anything
最近或者我有一些日常事务，只是等待下一个
recently or I have some go routine whose
job it is just wait for the next
无论是Zookeeper带来的任何意义，您都可以阅读该申请书
whatever it is from zookeeper in the
same sense that you might read the apply
频道和所有有趣的内容都会出现在应用程序中
Channel and just all kinds of
interesting stuff comes up on the apply
频道，这是一种更可能的结构方式，但是是的，您完全可以
channel so that's a more likely way to
structure this but yeah you're totally
通过线程或某种事件驱动的方法，您可以做某事
either through threading or some sort of
event-driven thing you can do something
否则，当您等待时是是，或者如果我之前的人都没有死
else while you're waiting yes yes or if
the person before me has neither died
也没有发布，这是我之前存在的文件，这意味着该客户端是
nor released it's a file before me
exists that means either that client is
仍然活着并仍在等待锁，或仍然活着并持有锁
still alive and still waiting for the
lock or still alive and holds the lock
我们真的不知道
we don't really know
只要客户端500仍然存在，它就会执行该操作（如果存在的话）
it does it as long as that client 500
still live if if this exists fails that
意味着两件事之一，要么是我的前任持有锁，要么是
means one of two things either my
predecessor held the lock and is
释放并删除了他们的文件，或者我的前任没有持有他们的锁
released it and deleted their file or my
predecessor didn't hold the lock they
退出并且Zookeeper删除了他们的文件，因为它是临时文件，因此
exited and zookeeper deleted their file
because it was an ephemeral file so
有两个原因可以减轻他的体重，或者四个
there's two reasons to come out of this
to come out of his weight or four they
存在以返回false，这就是为什么我们必须喜欢我们检查所有内容的原因
exist to return false and that's why we
have to like we check everything you
知道你真的不知道情况如何
know you really don't know what the
situation is after the exists completes
那也许是的，也许那可能需要工作听起来
that might that yeah maybe maybe that
could need to work that sounds
合理并且保留了可扩展性
reasonable
and it preserves the sort of scalable
的本质，每个需求发布仅涉及几个客户端，两个
nature of this and that each require
release only involves a few clients two
客户
clients
好吧，对我来说，这种模式实际上首先完全看到了这种模式。
alright this pattern to me actually
first saw this pattern a totally
线程系统的不同上下文和可伸缩锁
different context and scalable locks for
threading systems I go this end in for
在世界大部分地区，这被称为电子秤
most of the world this is called a scale
of a lock
我发现它是我现在见过的那些有趣的构造之一，因此
I find it one of those interesting
constructions I've ever seen now and so
就像让我印象深刻的是，动物园管理员能够表达它，这是很有价值的
like I'm impressed that zookeeper is
able to express it and it's a valuable
曾经说过关于为什么动物园管理员为什么的一些观点
construct having said that I'm a little
bit at sea about why zookeeper about why
本文完全讨论了锁，因为这些锁不是
the paper talks about locks at all
because these locks these locks are not
像线程锁一样走，因为在线程中没有线程的概念
like threading locks and go because in
threading there's no notion of threads
至少如果您不希望他们失败，那就没有失败的念头
failing at least if you don't want them
there to be there's no notions of
线程只是某种随机的死亡而已，所以实际上您唯一的一件事就是
threads just sort of randomly dying and
go and so really the only thing you're
摆脱互斥锁的确是这样，当您使用它时
getting out of a mutex it's really the
case and go that when you use it if
每个人都正确使用互斥锁，您将获得原子序列的原子性
everybody uses mutexes correctly you are
getting atomicity for the sequence of
互斥锁内部的操作，您知道是否要锁住然后
operations inside the mutex that you
know if you take out a lock and go and
你做47个不同的读写大量变量，然后释放锁
you do 47 different read and write a lot
of variables and then release the lock
如果每个人都遵循这种锁定策略，那么没人会看到
if everybody follows that locking
strategy nobody's ever going to see some
截止到一半时，数据的中间版本有点奇怪
sort of weird intermediate version of
the data as of halfway through you're
正确地更新它只会使事物变得原子无参数，这些锁不是
updating it right just makes things
atomic no argument these locks aren't
真的很喜欢，因为如果持有锁的客户端失败，
really like that because if the client
that holds the lock fails it just
释放锁，其他人可以拿起锁，因此它不会
releases the lock and somebody else can
pick up the lock so it does not
保证原子性，因为您可以获得部分故障和分布式系统
guarantee atomicity because you can get
partial failures and distributed systems
在这里，您不会真正获得普通线程代码的部分失败，所以如果
where you don't really get partial
failures of ordinary threaded code so if
当前的锁持有者拥有锁，需要更新一大堆东西
the current lock holder had the lock and
needed to update a whole bunch of things
在释放之前受那个锁保护的并且只在中途通过
that were protected by that lock before
releasing and only got halfway through
更新这些东西，然后崩溃，然后锁将被释放，您将
updating this stuff and then crashed
then the lock will get released you'll
得到锁，但是当您查看数据时，它是垃圾，因为它是
get the lock and yet when you go to look
at the data it's garbage because it's
只是它中间的任何随机种子
just whatever random seed it was in the
middle of
更新，因此这些锁本身并不提供相同的原子性
updated so there's these locks don't by
themselves provide the same atomicity
确保线程锁可以这样做，所以我们可以想象一下
guarantee that threading locks do and so
we're sort of left to imagine for
自己通过纸质，或者为什么要使用它们，或者为什么这样
ourselves by the paper or why you would
want to use them or why this is the sort
本文中的一些主要示例，我想如果您使用像
of some of the main examples in the
paper so I think if you use locks like
然后在一个分布式系统中进行排序，然后有两个常规选项
this then you sort in a distributed
system then you have two general options
一个人是每个获得锁的人都必须准备从某些地方清理
one is everybody who acquires a lock has
to be prepared to clean up from some
以前的灾难权，因此您获得了此锁定，然后查看您尝试的数据
previous disaster right so you acquire
this lock you look at the data you try
找出天哪，如果很多的前所有者崩溃了
to figure out gosh if the previous owner
of a lot crashed
您知道当我查看数据时，您知道如何修复数据以使
you know when I'm looking at the data
you know how can I fix the data to make
如何确定以前的所有者是否当机，我该如何解决
up how can I decide if the previous
owner crashed and what do I do to fix up
数据，然后您就可以玩该游戏，特别是如果约定是
the data and you can play that game
especially if the convention is that you
总是按照特定的顺序更新，您也许能够检测到
always update in a particular sequence
you may be able to detect where in that
顺序假设先前的所有者崩溃了，但是那是你
sequence the previous holder crashed
assuming they crashed but it's a you
知道这是一个棘手的游戏，需要您不需要的那种思考
know it's a tricky game the requires
thought of a kind you don't need for
就像线程锁定um的另一个原因，也许这些锁定是有意义的，如果
like thread locking um the other reason
maybe these locks would make sense is if
有种软锁可以保护一些无关紧要的东西
there's sort of soft locks protecting
something that doesn't really matter
因此，例如，如果您正在运行MapReduce作业，则地图任务会减少任务
so for example if you're running
MapReduce jobs map tasks reduce tasks
您可以使用这种锁来确保只有一个任务只有一个工人
you could use this kind of lock to make
sure only one task only one worker
执行每个任务，以便工人进行测试37，它将获得任务37的锁
executed each task so workers gonna run
test 37 it gets the lock for task 37
执行它会将其标记为已执行，并以不产生的方式很好地释放它
execute it marks it as executed and
releases it well the way not produce
无论如何，它实际上是针对崩溃工人的证明，因此，如果您抓住
works it's actually proof against
crashed workers anyway so if you grab a
锁定，您在MapReduce工作中途崩溃，那么下一个人
lock and you crash halfway through your
MapReduce job so what the next person
谁会得到您知道的锁，因为当您崩溃时，您的锁将被释放
who gets the lock you know because your
lock will be released when you crash the
下一个获得此版本的人会看到您尚未完成任务，仅我们
next version who gets it will see you
didn't finish the task and just we
执行它，这不是一个问题，因为MapReduce的定义方式
execute it and it's just not a problem
because of the way MapReduce is defined
因此尽管您仍然可以使用这些锁或某种软锁
so you could use these locks or some
kind of soft lock thing although anyway
而且您可能知道我们应该考虑的另一件事是
and you know maybe the other thing which
we should be thinking about is that some
这个版本可以用来做一些事情，比如选一个高手
version of this
be used to do things like elect a master
但是，如果我们在这里真正要做的是选举一位硕士，您知道我们可以使用
but if what we're really doing here is
electing a master you know we could use
像这样编写代码，这可能是一种合理的方法
code much like this and that would
probably be a reasonable approach yeah
哦，是的，所以请记住我在
oh yeah yeah yeah so the picking of
paper talk that remember the text in the
有人说它将删除准备好的文件，然后做一堆
paper were says it's going to delete the
ready file and then do a bunch of
更新文件，然后重新创建准备好的文件，即
updates to files and then recreate the
ready file that would that is a
一种奇妙的检测和应对方式，
fantastic way of sort of detecting and
coping with the possibility that the
先前持有的锁或先前的主人或中途坠毁的任何人
previous lock held or the previous
master or whoever it is crashed halfway
因为gosh永远不会创建就绪文件
through because gosh the ready file has
never be created
Inigo程序是的，很遗憾，这是可能的，而且您知道还可以，所以
Inigo program yeah sadly that is
possible and you know either okay so the
问题与Zookeeper无关，但是如果您正在编写线程代码并执行
question is nothing about zookeeper but
if you're writing threaded code and go a
线程在中途拿着锁时会崩溃而获取锁
thread acquires a lock could it crash
while holding the lock halfway through
按住锁应该做的任何事情，答案是
whatever stuff it's supposed to be doing
while holding a lock and the answer is
是的，实际上有一些方法可以使单个线程崩溃并消失
yes actually there are there are ways
for an individual thread to crash and go
哦，我忘记了他们可能会在哪里将某些恐慌除以零
oh I forget where they are maybe divide
by zero certain panics anyway you can do
它和我关于如何思考的建议是该程序现在
it and my advice about how to think
about that is that the program is now
坏了，你必须杀死它，因为在线程代码中
broken and you've got to kill it because
in threaded code the way the thing about
锁是当持有锁时，数据中的不变量不成立，因此
locks is that while the lock is held the
invariants in the data don't hold so
如果锁具坠毁，则无法继续进行操作，没有安全的方法
there's no way to proceed if the lock
holder crashes there's no safe way to
继续进行，因为您所知道的就是锁是不变的
proceed because all you know is whatever
the invariants were that the lock was
保护不再如此等等，如果您要继续，则必须
protecting no longer hold so and so and
if you do want to proceed you have to
将锁标记为“已持有”，以便其他任何人都无法获取它
leave the lock marked as held so that no
one else will ever be able to acquire it
而且您知道，除非您有一些聪明的主意，这几乎就是您拥有的方式
and you know unless you have some clever
idea that's pretty much the way you have
在线程程序中考虑它，因为这是一种
to think about it in a threaded program
because that's kind of the style with
如果您非常聪明，哪些人会编写线程锁定程序
which people write threaded lock
programs if you're super clever you
可以玩像这样的现成标志戏法一样的戏法，现在超级好
could play the same kinds of tricks like
this ready flag trick now it's super
努力去做，因为内存模型表明您无法依靠
hard and go because the memory model
says there is nothing you can count on
除非在关系发生之前发生过，否则如果您玩这个
except if there's a happens before
relationship so if you play this game of
编写更改一些变量，然后设置完成标志，但这并不意味着
writing changing some variables and then
setting a done flag that doesn't mean
除非您释放锁，否则其他人会获得锁，并且只有
anything unless you release a lock and
somebody else acquires a lock and only
那么关于什么顺序或是否可以
then can anything be said about the
order in which or in even whether the
更新发生，所以这很难，很难，要从
updates happen so this is very very hard
it rivairy hard and go to recover from a
保持锁在此处的线程崩溃可能更有可能
crash of a thread that holds the lock
here is maybe a little more possible
好吧好吧好吧，这就是我想和动物园管理员谈的全部
okay okay okay that's all I want to talk
about with zoo keeper
只有两个高价出价，一个是针对这些高价创意
it's just two pieces of high bid one is
at these clever ideas for high
通过读取任何副本获得性能，但是它们牺牲了一些
performance by reading from any replica
but the they sacrifice a bit of
一致性和无趣的另一个有趣之处是
consistency and the other interesting
thing uninteresting take-home is that
他们制定了这个API，的确确实使它们成为通用类
they worked out this API that really
does let them be a general-purpose sort
协调服务的方式，例如put get接口之类的简单方案
of coordination service in a way that
simpler schemes like put get interfaces
只是做不到，所以他们在这里制定了一组功能，使您可以
just can't do so they worked out a set
of functions here that allows you to do
编写迷你交易并建立自己的锁之类的东西就可以了
things like write mini transactions and
build your own locks and it all works
出来，虽然需要照顾好了，现在我想谈谈今天的文件
out although requires care okay now I
want to turn to today's paper which is
破解我们正在阅读便签纸的原因，有两个原因是
crack the the reason why we're reading a
crack paper it's a couple reasons one is
是因为它确实是为了容错而复制的，正如我们将看到的
is that it's it does replication for
fault tolerance and as we'll see the
您摆脱裂缝或其前代链复制的特性非常
properties you get out of crack or its
predecessor chain replication are very
与您从类似系统中获得的属性以有趣的方式有所不同
different in interesting ways from the
properties you get out of a system like
筏，所以我实际上要谈论的是，裂纹有点像
raft and so I'm actually going to talk
about so crack is sort of an
对称为链复制链复制的较旧方案的优化
optimization to an older scheme called
chain replication chain replications
实际上在现实世界中经常使用，有一堆系统
actually fairly frequently used in the
real world there's a bunch of systems
用它破解是对它的优化
that use it
crack is an optimization to it that
确实有一个类似的技巧-动物园管理员试图增加
actually does a similar trick -
zookeeper where it's trying to increase
通过允许读取两个副本到任何副本来消除杂草吞吐量，从而获得
weed throughput by allowing reads to two
replicas to any replicas so that you get
你知道副本数量增加读取性能的因素
you know number of replicas factor of
increase in the read performance the
裂纹的有趣之处在于它在保留的同时做到了这一点
interesting thing about crack is that it
does that while preserving
线性化能力与您知道的动物园管理员不同
linearise ability
unlike zookeeper which you know it
似乎是为了能够从他们必须牺牲的任何副本中读取
seemed like in order to be able to read
from any replica they had to sacrifice
新鲜度，因此，snot线性裂缝实际上设法
freshness and therefore snot
linearizable crack actually manages to
从任何副本进行这些读取，同时保持强一致性，我只是
do these reads from any replica while
preserving strong consistency I'm just
挺有趣的，所以首先我想谈谈旧的系统链
pretty interesting okay so first I want
to talk about the older system chain
复制青少年复制是一个，这只是您有多个方案
replication teen replication is a it's
just a scheme for you have multiple
您想要确保它们都看到正确的序列的副本，所以
copies you want to make sure they all
seen the same sequence of right so it's
像一个非常熟悉的基本概念，但是它是与筏不同的拓扑，所以
like a very familiar basic idea but it's
a different topology then raft so the
想法是有一个服务器链和链复制，第一个是
idea is that there's a chain of servers
and chain replication and the first one
当客户进入右方时，被称为头尾。
is called the head last one's called the
tail when a right comes in when a client
想写点东西说总是发送给Albright的客户
wants to write something say some client
it sends always Albright's get sent to
头部更新或替换其当前数据副本
the head the head updates its or
replaces its current copy of the data
客户写的，这样您就可以想象将密钥值存储起来，以便您
that the clients writing so you can
imagine be go put key value store so you
知道每个人是否都从您开始了解数据的版本a和
know if everybody started out with you
know version a of the data and under
正确的头过程时可能进行链复制，也许我们在写
chain replication when the head process
is the right and maybe we're writing
值B您知道头部只是将其a替换为B并向右传递
value B you know the head just replaces
its a with a B and passes the right down
每个节点看到正确替换的链时，写入其副本数据
the chain as each node sees the right it
replaces over writes its copy the data
当右方得到尾巴时，新数据将尾巴发送回给
the new data when the right gets the
tail the tail sends the reply back to
客户说我们完成了您的权利
the client saying we completed your
right
如果客户端要进行读取，则版权工作的方式就是读取该内容，然后将读取结果发送给
that's how rights work reads if a client
wants to do a read it sends the read to
尾巴读取尾巴的请求，尾巴只是从尾巴中回答
the tail the read request of the tail
and the tail just answers out of its
当前状态，所以如果我们要求这个对象是尾巴
current state so if we ask for this
whatever this object was the tail which
我希望当前的价值比杂草更简单
is I hope current values be weeds are a
good deal simpler
好吧，它应该思考一下为什么要链式复制
okay so it should think for a moment
like why to chain chain replication so
这不是破解，只是要清楚这是链复制链复制
this is not crack just to be clear this
is chain replication chain replication
是线性化的，您知道在没有故障的情况下，我们会
is linearizable you know in the absence
of failures what's going on is that we
本质上可以将其视为真正的，而不是思考的目的
can essentially view it as really than
the purposes of thinking about
一致性，这就是一台服务器，服务器可以看到所有权限，
consistency it's just this one server
the server sees all the rights and it
查看所有读取并一次处理它们，您知道读取将
sees all the reads and process them one
at a time and you know a read will just
查看所写的最新值，几乎所有内容
see the latest value that's written and
that's pretty much all there is to it
从角度看，如果没有崩溃，一致性是什么样的
from the point of view look if there's
no crashes what the consistency is like
很简单，故障恢复链背后的很多原理
pretty simple the failure recovery the a
lot of the rationale behind chain
复制是发生故障后您可以看到的一组状态
replication is that the set of states
you can see when after there's a failure
之所以受到限制，是因为这种非常规则的模式
is relatively constrained because of
this very regular pattern with how the
写入被传播，并且在高层次上发生了什么
writes get propagated and at a high
level what's going on is that any
承诺写入，即可以向客户端确认的任何速率
committed write that is any rate that
could have been acknowledged to a client
给写作客户或阅读中可能暴露的任何比率
to the writing client or any rate that
could have been exposed in a read
除非那个写达到
that'll neither of those will ever
happen unless that write reached the
为了使其到达尾巴，它必须在过程中通过它们
tail in order for it to reach the tail
it had to a pass through them in process
链中的每个节点，所以我们知道如果我们曾经接触过写
by every single node in the chain so we
know that if we ever exposed to write
曾经被认可的写入曾经用于读取，这意味着
ever acknowledged write ever use it to a
read that means every single node in the
尾巴必须知道正确的权利，我们不会遇到这种情况，例如您打电话给
tail must know about that right we don't
get these situations like if you'll call
图七图八和英国皇家空军的纸，你可以在那里理发
figure seven figure eight and RAF paper
where you can have just hair-raising
复杂性以及如果发生崩溃会导致不同副本的差异
complexity and how the different
replicas differ if there's a crash here
您知道它是提交的，还是在崩溃之前应该到达
you know either that it is committed or
it before the crash should reach some
要点，之后再没有其他地方，因为权利的进步
point and nowhere after that point
because the progress of rights has
总是菜单，因此如果没有权利，则到处都会知道已落实的权利
always menu so committed rights are
always known everywhere if a right isn't
承诺意味着在发生任何崩溃之前，都会打扰
committed that means that before
whatever crash it was that disturb the
系统到达该点之前某个地方的速率
system the rate of got into a certain
point everywhere before that point and
毫无疑问，实际上只有两种设置
nowhere after
point there's really the only two setups
在高水平的情况下，如果磁头出现故障，恢复也相对简单
and at a high level failure recovery is
relatively simple also if the head fails
然后近似到下一个节点可以简单地接管他的头，
then to a first approximation the next
node can simply take over his head and
没有其他事情需要完成，因为任何达到它的速率
nothing else needs to get done because
any rate that made it as far as the
第二个节点，但它是头部失败，因此正确将继续进行
second node while it was the head that
failed so that right will keep on going
如果发生撞车事故，我们会做出承诺，但是
and we'll commit if there's a rate that
made it to the head before a crash but
负责人没有很好地转发它，这绝对是没有人知道的承诺
the head didn't forward it well that's
definitely not committed nobody knows
关于它，我们绝对没有给它写一封感谢信
about it and we definitely didn't send
it an acknowledgment to the writing
客户，因为本文没有落到这里，所以我们没有义务做任何事情
client because the write didn't get down
here so we're not obliged to do anything
关于写它只会在失败之前到达一个崩溃的头，我可能是
about a write it only reached a crashed
head before it failed I may be the
客户我们犯了罪，但如果这个故事失败了，你不知道我们的问题是
client where we sinned but you know not
our problem if the tale fails it's
实际上非常相似，这个故事失败了下一个节点可以直接接管，因为
actually very similar the tale fails the
next node can directly take over because
故事所知道的一切，然后在节点之前就知道了，因为
everything the tale knew then next the
node just before it also knows because
故事只听到节点之前的消息，这有点
the tale only hears things from the node
just before it and it's a little bit
中间节点的复合体失败，但是基本上需要做的是
complex of an intermediate node fails
but basically what needs to be done is
我们需要将其从链中删除，现在可能有它拥有的权利
we need to drop it from the chain and
now there may be rights that it had
收到下一个节点尚未收到的消息，因此如果我们放下一个便条
received that the next node hasn't
received yet and so if we drop a note
在链外，前任可能需要重新发送对
out of the chain the predecessor may
need to resend recent rights to the to
它的新继任者权利概括地说就是复苏，这就是为什么
its new successor right that's the
recovery in a nutshell that's for why
这种结构为什么这而不是为什么这节经文
this construction why this instead of
something else like why this verse is
例如，包装的性能原因是，如果您还记得我们在筏子里
wrapped for example the performance
reason is that in raft if you recall we
你知道我们是否有领导者，一群人知道一些复制品
you know if we have a leader and a bunch
of you know some number of replicas
与领导者在一起不是在链中，我们得到了这些副本
right with the leader it's not in a
chain we got these the replicas are all
直接由领导者提供，因此，如果有客户权利或客户阅读
directly fed by the leader so if a
client right comes in or a client read
为此，领导者必须将其自身发送给每个副本
for that matter the the leader has to
send it itself to each of the replicas
而在链式复制中，领导者只需要执行一次，
whereas in chain replication the leader
on the head only has to do once and
这些美分在网络上实际上是相当昂贵的，因此这意味着
these cents on the network are actually
reasonably expensive and so that means
木筏首领的负载将高于链条上的负载
the load on a raft leader is going to be
higher than the load on a chain
复制领导者，所以这意味着您知道客户端的数量
replication leader and so that means
that you know as the number of client
您从客户那里获得的每秒请求数量上升了
requests per second that you're getting
from clients goes up a raft leader will
达到极限并停止比链式复制更快的速度
hit a limit and stop being able to get
faster sooner than a chain replication
头，因为它比链复制有更多的工作要做
head because it's doing more work than
the chain replication had another
链条复制和木筏之间有趣的区别在于，芦苇
interesting difference between chain
replication and raft is that the reeds
筏子上的所有东西也都需要由领导者看到的领导者来处理
in raft are all also required to be
processed by the leaders the leader sees
客户的每一个请求都在这里，负责人看到每个人
every single request from clients
where's here the head sees everybody
看到所有的权利，但只有尾巴看到芦苇的要求，所以可能有一个
sees all the rights but only a tail sees
the reed requests so there may be an
负载在头尾之间分配的程度
extent to which the load is sort of
split between the head and the tail
而不是专注于领导者，正如我之前提到的
rather than concentrated in the leader
and and as I mentioned before the
失败需要进行不同类型的分析，以考虑不同
failure different sort of analysis
required to think about different
故障场景比以前要简单得多，而且链复制也很容易，并且
failure scenarios is a good deal simpler
and chain replication than it is and
木筏，这是一个很大的动机，因为很难正确纠正这些问题。
raft and as a big motivation because
it's hard to get this stuff correct yes
是的，所以如果这个故事失败了，但它的前任已经看到了一项权利，那就是
yeah so if the tale fails but its
predecessor had seen a right that the
故事还没有看过，那么那个黑尔的失败基本上就是对的
tale hadn't seen then the failure of
that Hale basically commits that right
现在已下定决心，因为这已经达到了新的境界，因此他可以回应
is now committed because it's reached
the new tale and so he could respond to
客户端可能不会，因为您知道它不是尾巴
the client it probably won't because it
you know it wasn't a tail when it
收到了权利，因此客户可能会重新发送该权利，这太糟糕了，
received the right and so the client may
resend the right and that's too bad and
所以我们基本上可能需要重复抑制
so we need duplicate suppression
probably at the head basically all the
系统在谈论除了其他所有抑制之外的需求
systems were talking about require in
addition to everything else suppression
重复的客户请求是，您想知道谁的粉红心理设置
of duplicate client requests yes pink
psyche setting in you want to know who
做出关于如何解决这个问题的决定
makes the decisions about how to that's
a outstanding question the question is
或将问题改写一下，如果出现故障，例如
or rephrase the question a bit if
there's a failure like or suppose the
第二个节点停止与头部对话
second node stops being able to talk to
the head can this second node just take
它可以自行决定，天哪，脑袋似乎在想，我要
over can it decide for itself gosh the
head seems to thought away I'm gonna
接过他的头，告诉客户跟我说话，而不是老头，但是
take over his head and tell clients to
talk to me instead of the old head but
您认为这不像什么计划
what do you think that's not like a plan
根据通常的假设，我们对网络的行为做出了决定
with the usual assumptions we make about
how the network behaves that's a recipe
如果您完全按照我说的去做，那当然可以
for split brain right if you do exactly
what I said because of course what
真正发生的是，看起来网络失败了
really happened was that look the
network failed here the head is totally
活着，脑袋认为它的继任者已经死了，你知道继任者
alive and the head thinks its successor
has died you know the successors
实际上还活着，它认为头部已经死了，他们俩都说天哪，
其他服务器似乎已经死了，我要接管，头要去
other server seems to have died I'm
gonna take over and the head is gonna
说哦，我只是一个唯一的复制品，我知道你扮演的是头和尾
say oh I'll just be a sole replica and I
you know act as the head and the tail
因为其余的变更似乎已经消失，第二，我会做
because the rest of the change seems to
have gone away and second I'll do the
同一件事，现在我们有两个独立的裂脑版本
same thing and now we have two
independent split brain versions of the
数据将逐渐不同步，因此这种构造无法证明
data which will gradually get out of
sync so this construction is not proof
针对网络分区，并且没有针对拆分的防御措施
大脑，这在实践中意味着如果它本身不能被使用，就像
brain and what that means in practice is
if it cannot be used by itself it's like
我们的后兜里有一件有用的东西，但这还不完整
a helpful thing to have in our back
pocket but it's not a complete
复制的故事，所以它是非常常用的，但是在这个故事中
replication story so it's it's very
commonly used but it's used in this
始终存在外部权威的程式化方式
决定谁是这样的连锁店，呼吁谁在世，谁在
chain that decides who's that sort of
makes a call on who's alive and who's
死了，并确保每个人都同意关于谁构成
dead and make sure everybody agrees on a
single story about who constitutes the
变化从来没有任何分歧有些人认为变化是没有
change there's never any disagreement
some people think the change is this no
有些人认为链条是另一个节点，所以通常是什么
and some people think the chain is this
other node so what's that's usually
被称为配置管理器，它的工作仅仅是监视程序的活跃性，
called as a configuration manager and
its job is just a monitor aliveness and
每次Isis每次看到所有服务器时
every time it sees of all the servers
every time Isis every time the
配置管理器认为服务器已死，它发出了新的消息
configuration manager thinks the
server's dead it sends out a new
您知道该链具有新定义的配置
configuration in which you know that
this chain has a new definition had
不管是什么尾巴，配置管理器认为的那台服务器可能
whatever tail and that's server that the
configuration manager thinks is that may
或可能没有死，但我们不在乎，因为每个人都必须遵守
or may not be dead but we don't care
because everybody is required to follow
那么您的配置，就不会有任何分歧
then your configuration
and so there can't be any disagreement
因为只有一方做出这些决定不会不同意
because there's only one party making
these decisions not going to disagree
当然，您如何使用自己提供的容错服务
with itself of course how do you make a
service that's fault tolerant and
不会不同意自己，但是如果有
doesn't disagree with itself but doesn't
suffer from split brain if there's
网络分区，答案是配置管理器
network partitions and the answer to
that is that the configuration manager
通常使用愤怒或paxos，或者在使用裂纹动物园管理员的情况下
usually uses wrath or paxos or in the
case of crack zookeeper which itself of
课程是基于类似筏的计划构建的，因此您可以按照通常的完整设置
course is built on a raft like scheme so
so you to the usual complete set up in
您的数据中心是基于它的配置管理器
your data center is it you have a
configuration manager it's it's based on
或在PAC之后或任何其他方式，所以它具有容错能力，不会遭受分裂
or after PACs or whatever so it's fault
tolerant and does not suffer from split
大脑，然后如果您知道房间，就将数据拆分成一堆变化
brain and then you split up your data
over a bunch of change if you know room
里面有一千台服务器，您知道链条，就知道
with a thousand servers in it and you
have you know chain a you know it's
这些服务器或配置管理器决定更改应
these servers or the configuration
manager decides that the change should
看起来链a是由服务器一服务器到服务器三链制成的
look like chain a is made of server one
server to server three chain be you know
服务器5超过6的服务器，它告诉所有人整个列表
server for server 5 over 6 whatever and
it tells everybody this whole list it's
所有客户都知道所有服务器，每个服务器都知道
all the clients know all the servers
know and the individual servers opinions
关于其他服务器是存活还是死亡的信息完全不在这里或那里
about whether other servers are alive or
dead are totally neither here nor there
如果此服务器确实死了，则需要头部继续尝试
if this server really does die then then
the head is required to keep trying
无限期，直到我从配置中猜出新配置
indefinitely until I guess a new
configuration from the configuration
经理不允许对谁还活着，谁死了做出决定
manager not allowed to make decisions
about who's alive and who's dead what's
哦，男孩，你有一个严重的问题，所以
that
oh boy you've got a serious problem so
这就是为什么您使用筏进行复制的原因，请确保已打开不同的副本
that's why you replicated using raft
make sure the different replicas are on
不同的电源为整个工程供电，但是我已经建立了这个结构
different power supplies the whole works
but this this construction I've set up
这是非常普遍的，这是打算使用链复制的方式
here it's extremely common and it's how
chain replication is intended to be used
打算如何使用裂纹及其逻辑，就像链条一样
how cracks intend to be used and the
logic of it is that like chain require
复制，如果您不必担心分区和脑裂的话，您可以
replication if you don't have to worry
about partition and split brain you can
使用链构建非常高速高效的复制系统
build very high speed efficient
replication systems using chain
例如复制，因此这些人您知道数据复制和
replication for example so these
individual you know data replication and
我们将数据分别分摊给许多链，这些链可以是
we're sharding the data over many chains
individually this these chains can be
被构建为特定事物最有效的方案
built to be just the most efficient
scheme for the particular kind of thing
无论您复制什么，您可能都会读沉重的沉重的沉重的负担，但是我们不会
that you're replicating you may read
heavy right heavy whatever but we don't
不得不过多地担心分区，然后所有的担忧都集中了
have to worry too much about partitions
and then all that worry is concentrated
在可靠的非裂脑配置管理器中
in the reliable non split-brain
configuration manager
好的，所以您的问题是为什么我们在这里使用链复制而不是
okay so your question is why are we
using chain replication here instead of
木筏好吧，所以这就像一个完全合理的问题
raft okay so it's like a totally
reasonable question um the the it
对于这种构造来说，实际上并不重要，因为即使我们正在使用
doesn't really matter for this
construction because even if we're using
在这里，我们仍然需要一方来做出决定
raft here we still need one party to
make a decision with which there can be
关于如何将数据划分为一百种不同意见没有分歧
no disagreement about how the data is
divided over our hundred different
复制组正确，所以您所知道的和我需要的是一种大型系统
replication groups right so all you know
and I need kind of big system you're
拆分分片或拆分数据
splitting your sharding or splitting up
the data
有人需要决定如何将数据分配给不同的复制
somebody needs to decide how the data is
assigned to the different replication
组，随着您获得或多或少的硬件更多的数据，它必须随着时间而改变
groups this has to change over time as
you get more or less Hardware more data
或其他什么，如果配置管理器说的没问题
or whatever so if nothing else the
configuration manager is saying well
看起来您知道键以a或B开头，然后C或D甚至是此处
look you know the keys start with a or B
goes here or then C or D goes here even
如果您现在在这里使用Paxos，还有一个较小的问题，如果我们不吃饭
if you use Paxos here now there's also
this smaller question if we didn't eat
你知道我们应该用于复制的是链式复制
you know what should we use for
replication should be chain replication
或paxos或木筏或其他任何人，人们会做一些不同的事情
or paxos or raft or whatever and people
do different things some people do
实际上使用基于Paxos的复制（如扳手），我认为我们要
actually use Paxos based replication
like spanner which I think we're gonna
在学期的后期有这种结构，但实际上它使用Paxos来
look at later in the semester has this
structure but it actually uses Paxos to
复制数据的权限，您知道您可能不想使用的原因
replicate rights for the data you know
the reason why you might not want to use
PAC如此泛滥，以至于使用该链条可以说效率更高
PAC so so raft is that it's arguably
more efficient to use this chain
结构，因为它减少了引导器上的负载，并且可能会或可能不会
construction because it reduces the load
on the leader and that may or may not be
一个关键问题是赞成r徒Paxos的原因是他们不必
a critical issue the a reason to favor
rafter Paxos is that they do not have to
等待一个滞后的副本，此链复制存在性能问题
wait for a lagging replica this chain
replication has a performance problem
如果这些复制品之一很慢，因为
that if one of these replicas is slow
because even for a moment
你知道，因为每个速率都必须遍历每个副本，即使是一个慢速
you know because every rate has to go
through every replica even a single slow
复制品会减慢所有提供的所有操作的速度，可能会造成很大的损害
replica slows down all offer all right
operations and I can be very damaging
您知道是否有成千上万的服务器可能在任何给定时间做了
you know if you have thousands of
servers probably did any given time you
知道其中有七个人出去吃午餐，或者因为某人的
know seven of them are out to lunch or
unreliable or slow because somebody's
安装知道这些内容的新软件，因此拥有它会有些损害
installing new software who knows what
and that so it's a bit damaging to have
每个请求都会受到最慢的服务器的限制，而brafton paxos
every request be sort of limited by the
slowest server whereas brafton paxos
好吧，例如追随者之一是如此，所以没关系
well it's so rad for example if one of
the followers is so it doesn't matter
因为那个领导者只需要等待多数，而不必等待
because that leader only has to wait for
a majority it doesn't have to wait for
他们所有人都知道，最终他们都必须跟上，但是筏好得多
all of them you know ultimately they all
have to catch up but raft is much better
抵抗瞬态减速和一些基于Paxos的系统
resisting transient slowdown and some
Paxos based systems although not really
木筏还擅长处理副本在其中的可能性
raft are also good at dealing with the
possibility that the replicas are in
不同的数据中心，也许彼此相距很远，因为
different data centers and maybe far
from each other and because you only
需要多数，您不必一定要等待确认
need a majority you don't have to
necessarily wait for acknowledgments
来自遥远的数据中心，这样也可以使人们使用Paxos Raft
from a distant data center and so that
can also leads people to use paxos raft
像多数方案一样，而不是链式复制，但这有点像
like majority schemes rather than chain
replication but this is sort of a it
很大程度上取决于您的工作量以及您要实现的目标，但这
depends very much on your workload and
what you're trying to achieve but this
我不知道它的整体架构是否通用，但它非常
overall architecture is in I don't know
if it's Universal but it's extremely
共同
common
像有意拓扑一样，对于不中断网络的网络来说，
like intentional topologies okay the for
a for a network that's not broken the
通常的假设是，所有计算机都可以通过
usual assumption is that all the
computers can talk to each other through
网络，因为有人踩到电缆或
the network for networks that are broken
because somebody stepped on a cable or
一些路由器配置错误，可能会发生任何疯狂的事情
some routers misconfigured any crazy
thing can happen
因此，绝对是由于缺少配置，您可能会遇到这样的情况：
so absolutely due to miss configuration
you can get a situation where you know
这两个节点可以与配置管理器和
these two nodes can talk to the
configuration manager and the
配置经理认为先生，他们起来了，但是他们不能互相交谈，所以
configuration managers think sir they're
up but they can't talk to each other so
是的，这是这项权利的杀手，因为其他配置
yes and and that's a killer for this
right because other configuration
经理以为他们不能和其他男孩说话，就像
manager thinks that are up they can't
talk to each other boy it's just like
这是一场灾难，如果您需要系统对此进行抵抗，那么您
it's a disaster and if you need your
system to be resistant to that then you
需要有一个更仔细的配置管理器，您需要在其中添加逻辑
need to have a more careful
configuration manager you need logic in
配置经理说，天哪，我只会从这些中结出一条链
the configuration manager that says gosh
I'm only gonna form a chain out of these
服务不仅可以与我交谈，而且可以彼此交谈，并且
services not only I can talk to that but
they can talk to each other and sort of
明确检查，我不知道这是否常见，我是说我不会
explicitly check and I don't know if
that's common I mean I'm gonna guess not
但是如果您非常小心，那么即使我们谈论过
but if you were super careful you'd want
to because even though we talked about
网络分区就像一个抽象，实际上您可以获得
network partition that's like a
abstraction and in reality you can get
可以与其他人交谈的任何组合，有些可能非常有害
any combination of who can talk to who
else and some are may be very damaging
好吧，我下个礼拜再见
okay I'm gonna wrap up and see you next
week